Guide to the Stephen Rodefer Papers, 1955-1994
Department of Special Collections
Stephen Rodefer Papers,
1955-1994
Special Collections M693
Rodefer, Stephen
18.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Purchased, 1994.
BIOGRAPHY
Stephen Rodefer's professional life has proven as eclectic and wide-ranging as the poetic voice emerging from his numerous books. As educator, he has taught undergraduate seminars at San Francisco State University, the University of California at San Diego, Jesus College at Cambridge University--and creative arts classes to fourth graders at the Malcolm X School; as prose writer, his work has been reprinted in publications as diverse as Wet, Downbeat, and Contrast II; and as poet, his narrative voice ranges from interpretive "translations" of the ancient Greek anthology, Lucretius, and Villon, to the consciously modern (if not post-modern) voice of Four Lectures or Passing Duration.
Born in 1940 in Bellaire, Ohio, Rodefer studied art history at Amherst College in Massachusetts. He received a master's degree in Language and Literature from the State University of New York at Buffalo, where he studied with Charles Olson and began a dissertation on the life and work of Robert Creeley, the notes for which are part of this collection. Also during this period, he attended the 1965 Berkeley Poetry Conference, which he describes as a sort of induction into the world of the New American Poetry represented by attendees like Gary Snyder, Allen Ginsberg, Robert Creeley, LeRoi Jones (later Amiri Baraka). He received an M.F.A. degree from San Francisco State University in 1981.
He has served as assistant professor of English and co-director of the creative writing program at the University of New Mexico, lecturer in English at San Francisco State University, curator of the Archive for New Poetry and visiting lecturer at the University of California at San Diego, and held a number of visiting lectureships at other schools and universities. As well as writing for magazines in both poetry and journalistic prose, Rodefer has been associated with their production: he edited Fervent Valley: A Magazine for the Arts (1972-1975); was contributing editor for Zyzzyva, and became involved with L=A=N=G=U=A=G=E magazine, an important journal of so-called language poetry. Since 1972, he has been active in the Bay Area's Poets Theater as both performer and writer/producer; his plays "A & C: an Idyl in One Act" and "Tennyson" were staged in 1983.
Rodefer's translations include After Lucretius, Villon, Orpheus (from Rilke's work) and Safety, a selection from Sappho and the Greek anthology. He is the author of The Knife, One Or Two Love Poems from the White World, The Bell Clerk's Tears Keep Flowing, Plane Debris, Oriflamme Day, Emergency Measures, and Four Lectures, which in 1983 was awarded the Annual Book Award by the American Poetry Center in San Francisco.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
Although the bulk of this collection is divided between Stephen Rodefer's manuscripts and correspondence, there are also several other series of note within the collection. The "Personal Business" series includes documents pertaining to Rodefer and his family, while "Printed Matter" contains programs, announcements of readings, and non-manuscript matter. "Manuscripts by Others" contains drafts of works by others ranging in date from the late 1950s to early 1990s, while the date range of "Fervent Valley Manuscripts" and Poets Theater Manuscripts" is understandably narrower. The photo collection contains mostly photos of Rodefer and his family, identified and dated when possible. The audio-visual collection ranges from early home movies shot by Howard Rodefer, to recent videotapes of readings and performances, to audiotapes of favorite music and readings by Robert Creeley, Basil Bunting, and Stephen Rodefer himself.
The correspondence series is organized by origin; personal correspondence, whether incoming or outgoing, is alphabetical, when the full name is known. Unknown authors, or recipients addressed only by their first names, are in folders arranged alphabetically under "unidentified mixed", while limited correspondence--single letters to or by an individual--are located in "mixed correspondence" within the series, arranged alphabetically as well. Rodefer's "Teaching and University Materials" are organized chronologically, with his "Archives for New Poetry Materials" from his stint at UC San Diego set off at the beginning of the series, and various coursepacks from his teaching career at the end. Rodefer's own manuscripts have been subdivided: the series begins with papers from his college career and early graduate school career, moves on to materials pertaining to his unfinished PhD. thesis on Robert Creeley, and finishes with Rodefer's "mature work," which is arranged alphabetically. Some of Rodefer's journalism is interleaved among the poetry; it is reproduced in the "journalism and reviews" section, along with the major reviews of Rodefer's writing. Mixed folders, which contain manuscripts compiled without specific title but as gift, submission, or commemoration of an occasion, are arranged chronologically at the end of the manuscript series.
SERIES DESCRIPTION
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE
  The correspondence series is organized by origin; personal correspondence, whether incoming or outgoing, is alphabetical, when the full name is known. Unknown authors, or recipients addressed only by their first names, are in folders arranged alphabetically under "unidentified mixed", while limited correspondence--single letters to or by an individual--are located in "mixed correspondence" within the series, arranged alphabetically as well.
- SERIES II: PERSONAL BUSINESS
  This series includes documents pertaining to Rodefer and his family.
- SERIES III: MANUSCRIPTS BY OTHERS
  This series contains drafts of works by others, ranging in date from the late 1950s to early 1990s
- SERIES IV: TEACHING/ UNIVERSITY MATERIALS
  This series is organized chronologically, with his "Archives for New Poetry Materials" from his stint at UC San Diego set off at the beginning of the series, and various coursepacks from his teaching career at the end.
- SERIES V: RODEFER MANUSCRIPTS
  The series begins with papers from Rodefer's college career and early graduate school career, moves on to materials pertaining to his unfinished PhD. thesis on Robert Creeley, and finishes with Rodefer's "mature work," which is arranged alphabetically. Some of Rodefer's journalism is interleaved among the poetry; it is reproduced in the "journalism and reviews" section, along with the major reviews of Rodefer's writing. Mixed folders, which contain manuscripts compiled without specific title but as gift, submission, or commemoration of an occasion, are arranged chronologically at the end of the manuscript series.
- SERIES VI: SUPPLEMENTARY MATERIALS
- SERIES VII: PHOTOS
  This series contains mostly photos of Rodefer and his family, identified and dated when possible
- SERIES VIII: AUDIO-VISUAL MATERIALS
  This series ranges from early home movies shot by Howard Rodefer, to recent videotapes of readings and performances, to audiotapes of favorite music and readings by Robert Creeley, Basil Bunting, and Stephen Rodefer himself.
CONTAINER LIST
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE
  - Subseries: Outgoing Business Correspondence
    - Amherst College (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - to Lee Bartlett (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Berkeley Unified School program proposal (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - to Brobeck, Phleger & Harrison: correspondence (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - misc. business correspondence (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Description of Project" for Macdowell/Rockefeller n.d.(AMs reprint) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - domestic matters/tax information (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - fellowship applications and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - to Lawrence Ferlinghetti (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - to Allen Ginsberg (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - to George Minkhoff (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - misc. job correspondence (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - NEA applications and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Poetry Center correspondence (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Poetry Flash correspondence (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - poetry readings: tour correspondence (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - submission queries (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - teaching employment correspondence (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - unidentified outgoing business: A-D (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - unidentified outgoing business: E-L (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - unidentified outgoing business: M-Z (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Subseries: Outgoing Personal Correspondence
    - Steve Benson (4 als, 1 tls) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Charles Bernstein (6 als, 3 pc) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Meghan Boucher (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Felix Brenner (1 pc) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Summer Brenner (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Margery Cantor (34 als, 4 tls, 8 pc) (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - Clark Coolidge (6 als, 1 pc) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Andrew Crozier (5 als, 3 tls) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Michael Davidson (15 als,2 tls) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Jean Day (38 als, 5 tls, 8 pc) (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
    - Jeff Derksen (2 als) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Johanna Drucker (9 als, 5 pc) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Kelly Feeney (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Ben Friedlander (11 als, 1 pc) (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - John Granger (10 als, 1 pc) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Lyn Hejinian (6 als, 2 tls) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Andrea Hollowell (19 als, 3 tls, 1 pc, 1 valentine) (Box 2, Folder 17-21)
    - Fanny Howe (6 als, 3 tls) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Howard Junker (5 als) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Jean Lowe (20 als, 7 tls, 6 pc, 2 als) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Andrea Mastor (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Rod Mengham (3 als) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Michael Palmer (1 als) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Pat Reed (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Benjamin Rodefer (7 als, 3 tls, 1 pc) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Dorothy Rodefer (3 als, 1 als) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Howard Rodefer (4 als, 1 pc) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Jesse Rodefer (5 als, 3 tls, 2 pc) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Penny Rodefer (6 als, 13 pc) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Rik Rodefer (2 als) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Rodefer Family (6 als, 1 tls, 30 pc) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Susan Rodefer (2 als) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - C.M. Rosser/ Rodefer (1 als) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Lydia Calman Shakespeare (25 als, 6 tls, 4 pc) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Ron Silliman (7 als, 6 tls, 1 pc) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Lenny Silverberg (5 als, 2 tls) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Chris Tysh (3 als, 2 pc) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Rosemarie and Keith Waldrop (6 als, 1 tls) (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Judy Yingst (1 als) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Geoff Young (14 als, 8 tls, 2 pc) (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
    - mixed folders: A-B (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - mixed folders: C (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - mixed folders: D-E (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - mixed folders: F-H (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - mixed folders: J-L (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - mixed folders: M-N (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - mixed folders: O-P (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - mixed folders: R-S (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - mixed folders: T-Z (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Subseries: Incoming Personal Correspondence
    - Don Allen (4 tls, 1 pc) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Michael Amnasan (4 als, 2 tls) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Michael Anderson (1 als, 2 tls) (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Bruce Andrews (2 als, 3 tls, 2 pc) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Theodore Baird (5 als, 1 tls) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Lee Bartlett (2 als, 9 tls, 1 pc) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Steve Benson (3 tls, 2 als, 2 pc) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Bill Berkson (4 tls, 11 pc) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Charles Bernstein (5 tls, 4 als, 11 pc) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Meghan Boucher (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Felix Brenner (3 als, 1 tls, 1 pc, 1 fb ms) (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Summer Brenner (29 als, 12 tls, 13 pc) (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Summer Brenner (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Manuel Brito (2 tls) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Gerald Burns (5 tls, 1 pc, 5 GB ms, 4 off-prints, 6 pictures) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - George Butterick (30 tls) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Margery Cantor (34 als, 21 pc) (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
    - Victor Coleman (20 tls, 5 als, 2 pc)) (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
    - Albert Cook (4 tls, 4 als, 1 pc) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Clark Coolidge (17 tls) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Robert Creeley (5 tls, 4 als, 9 pc) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Andrew Crozier (26 tls, 14 als) (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - Lynne Cutler (2 als) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Michael Davidson (10 tls) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Jean Day (15 als, 6 pc, 1 handmade boxed birthday card) (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
    - Jeff Derksen (4 tls, 2 als) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Edward Dorn (4 als, 1 pc) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Johanna Drucker (6 tls, 7 als, 9 pc, with 2 drawings) (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Clayton Eschelman (9 als, 6 tls) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Ben Friedlander (9 tls, 4 als, 5 pc) (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
    - Allen Ginsberg (4 tls, 2 als, 3 pc) (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Michael Glossen (16 als, tape and inserts) (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
    - Larry Goodell (23 als, 17 pc, and inserts) (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Carla Harryman (1 tls, 2 als, 2 pc) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Jim Hartz (6 als, 1 pc) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Robert Hass--see series II, box 16: recommendations
    - Lyn Hejinian (11 tls) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Sarah Herbold (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Leland Hickman (11 tls, 1 pc) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Jack Hirschman (7 als, 3 pc) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Andrea Hollowell (21 als, 7 pc, MS) (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
    - Cathleen Hoolihan Burke (85 als, 13 pc, with inserts and pictures) (Box 7, Folder 13-16)
    - Cathleen Hoolihan Burke (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - Fanny Howe (5 als, 6 tls, 3 pc) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Kim Jensen (1 als) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Howard Junker (5 als, 1 tls, 4 pc) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Galway Kinnell (1 tls) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Mary Kosenka (5 als, 5 pc) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Denise Levertov (2 als, 1 tls, 2 pc) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Julia Lisella (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Jean Lowe (35 als, 16 pc, wedding materials) (Box 8, Folder 11-14)
    - Andrea Mastor (3) (Box 8, Folder 15-17)
    - Steve McCaffrey (9 tls) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Maria McVarish (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Rod Mengham (1 als, 1 pc) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Laura Moriarty (7 als, 1 pc, Ms) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Jill Parchuk (4 als, 2 tls) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Bill Pearlman (56 als, 3 pc) (Box 9, Folder 6-9)
    - Roger Petrol (13 als, 9 pc, with Ms) (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
    - Tom Raworth (16 als, 1 tls, 4 pc) (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Stan Rice (5 tls, 4 als) (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Benjamin Rodefer (12 als, 5 tls, 4 pc, with inserts) (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
    - Dorothy Rodefer (46 als, 5 pc) (Box 9, Folder 16-18)
    - Dorothy Rodefer (3) (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - Howard Rodefer (10 als, 2 tls, 3 pc, with inserts) (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - Jesse Rodefer (41 als, 18 pc) (Box 10, Folder 6-8)
    - Penny Rodefer (65 als, 15 pc, with inserts and Ms) (Box 10, Folder 9-13)
    - Richard Rodefer (13 als, 1 pc) (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Susan Rodefer (5 als, 1 tls, 2 pc) (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Lydia Calman Shakespeare (15 als, 1 tls, 3 pc, with inserts) (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Ron Silliman (7 tls, 3 pc) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Bill Sylvester (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Betsy Tapia (9 als) (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Chris Tysh (6 tls, 1 als, 1 pc) (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Rosemarie Waldrop (7 tls, 2 als) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Donald Wesling (14 tls, 3 als, with inserts) (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Philip Whalen (5 als) (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Geoffrey Young ((36 tls, 21 als, 43 pc, with inserts and Ms) (Box 11, Folder 9-13)
    - unidentified A-E (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - unidentified: F-Z (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - mixed folder: A (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - mixed folder: B-Br (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - mixed folder: Br-Bz (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - mixed folder: C (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - mixed folder: Da-Dol (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - mixed folder: Dom-Ez (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - mixed folder: Fa-Fe (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - mixed folder: Ff-Fo (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - mixed folder: Fp-Fz (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - mixed folder: Ga-Gi (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - mixed folder: Gi-Gz (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - mixed folder: Ha-Hi (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - mixed folder: Hj-Hz (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - mixed folder: I-J (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - mixed folder: K-Ke (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - mixed folder: Ki-Kz (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - mixed folder: La-Li (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - mixed folder: Lo-Lz (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - mixed folder: M-Ma (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - mixed folder: Mb-Me (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - mixed folder: Mi-Mz (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - mixed folder: N-O (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - mixed folder: P-Patt (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - mixed folder: Patt-Paz (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - mixed folder: Pb-Pc (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - mixed folder: Pf-Pz (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - mixed folder: Ra-Re (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - mixed folder: Rf-Rz (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - mixed folder: Sa-Sg (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - mixed folder: Sh-Si (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - mixed folder: Sj-Sz (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - mixed folder: T-U (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - mixed folder: V (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - mixed folder: Wa-Wi (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - mixed folder: Wj-Wz (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - mixed folder: X-Z (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - letters to Anne Lowe re wedding (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - letters to other than Stephen Rodefer (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Subseries: Incoming Business Correspondence
    - ACTS/ White Rabbit conference on Spicer (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Black Mountain Poetry Conference (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Cuba Youth Brigade (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - English Speaking Union (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Poetry 1978 Conference (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Mixed folder: A (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - mixed folder: B (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - mixed folder: C (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - mixed folder: D-H (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - mixed folder: I-N (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - mixed folder: O-R (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - mixed folder: S-T (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - mixed folder: U-Z (Box 15, Folder 16)
- SERIES II: PERSONAL BUSINESS
  - Subseries: General
    - Amherst College documents (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - concerning Felix Brenner (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - concerning Dorothy Shackelford Rodefer (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - concerning Rodefer-Gleason Glass Co. bankruptcy (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - concerning S. Rodefer (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - concerning S. Rodefer: medical records: restricted (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - C.V. and Biographical data (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Fervent Valley: organizational materials (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - list of Poets' Theater plays; 1980s (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - memo from C.M.R. with plans of family house, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - passports, identification cards (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - professional documents--certification, etc. c.1966 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - professional documents: letters of recommendation for 1977-8 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - professional documents: letters on file at SUNY Buffalo through 1992 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - resignation from poetry, with others (AMsS) (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Rossall School materials (2) (Box 16, Folder 16-17)
    - wedding materials: July 7, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Western Reserve Academy reports, etc. 1956-58 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Subseries: Printed Matter
    - Alternative Press: postcards (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Amherst College: misc. class handouts c.1958-63 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Amherst College: Rolfe Humphries' class handouts, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - announcements not re S. Rodefer (2) (Box 17, Folder 4-7)
    - announcements re S. Rodefer, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - announcements re S. Rodefer (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Berkeley Poetry Conference program, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Black Mountain Poetry Conference, 1987 (2) (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "Billy's First Date" Class Play, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Catholic marriage pamphlets given S. Rodefer, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Duffy, Eamon "A University Sermon..." 1992 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Ephemeral Publications: "Involution" (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Ephemeral Publications: Scree (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "Lesbian/Gay Refugee Program at MCC" Jul. 15, 1980 (TMs) (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - misc. reprints and reviews by others (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Poets Theater Announcements (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - "Reserve Record," Western Reserve Academy, 1956-8 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - ROVA Saxophone materials from Russian trip, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Talking Poetry interview reprint, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Wedding Poem by Laura Moriarty, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 23)
- SERIES III: MANUSCRIPTS BY OTHERS
  - Subseries: General
    - Armstrong, ?. "Me and Steve's Weekend" (AMsS reprint) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Barker, Lucy. Poems (TMsS with ALS) (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Butterick, George "The Evidence for Cybele" (TMs reprint) (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Cameron, John A. "A Sermon on Columbus Day" (TMs reprint) (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Dawson, Fielding. "The Major Circle," "Straight Lines" (TMs with AN) (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Friedlander, Ben. "Add to this Rhetoric" (TMs with TLS, AN) (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Friedlander, Ben: "for Andrea Hollowell" (TMs with AN) (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Friedlander, Ben: poem (TMs) (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Friedlander, Ben: reviews (TMs with TLS, AN) (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Gachi, Gary. Poems (TMsS and TMs S reprint with ANS) (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Gleason, Jan. First 3 pages of short story (TMs with ANS) (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Goodell, Larry. Poems (TMsS with AN) (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Goodell, Larry: "Shaman Song" (TMs with TLS) (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Grenier, Robert "Tennyson" (TMs with ALS) (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Robert "Old Nestor's Pipe" (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Hammond, Mac "The Metonymic Poem" (TMs reprint) (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Hollowell, Andrea. Diary 1989 (AMs reprint and ALS) (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Hollowell, Andrea. Diary 1989: 2 of 3 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Hollowell, Andrea. Diary 1989: 3 of 3 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Hollowell, Andrea: diary 1992 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Hollowell, Andrea: diary July 9-22 (AMs reprint) (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Hollowell, Andrea: "Logic in the Light of Day" (TMs reprint with AN) (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Hollowell, Andrea: poems (TMs with ALS) (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Hollowell, Andrea: "Y" Prologue (TMs with ALS) (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Ignatow, David "William Carlos Williams and Wallace Stevens: Two of a Kind" (TMs reprint with TLS) (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Jensen, Kim from To Be (TMs with ALS) (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Jungle, Terese poems (TMs with ALS) (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Levy, Andrew poems (TMsS) (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Lifshin, Lynn poems (TMs) (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - MacAdams, Lewis poems (TMsS with ALS) (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Marshall, Jack trans. of Rilke elegies (TMsS reprint with ALS) (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Mastor, Andrea poems (1) (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Mastor, Andrea: poems (2) (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Mastor, Andrea: "The Square and the Oblong" (TMs reprint) (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Maybeck High School students, papers on Plane Debris (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Mc Anally, John "A Diet" (TMs with AN reprint and ALS) (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Miller, Mark poem (AMsS) (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Mittenthal, Robert poems 1986-7 (TMs with ALS) (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Molnar, Michael translations (TMs and TLS reprint) (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Murray, Arthur "Advice to Tall Girls" (TMs) (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Oakes, Katie "on Rodefer" (AMs reprint) (Box 19, Folder 2)